Sean McAuliffe

Middlesex, NJ 08846 coachmcauliffe@gmail.com +1 973 216 4119

2x Co-Founder & Solutions Architect, with an additional 8 years of an analytics background. Highly proficient on the AWS platform, with a focus on serverless architectures. Currently working towards AWS Professional Solutions Architect cert.

Authorized to work in the US for any employer

Work Experience

Co-Founder and CTO

En Place Technologies - Jersey City, NJ August 2021 to Present

- Designed Incyte, an application monitoring system, RUM system, and next-generation user tracking in one platform with savings of 30% compared to multi-vendor solutions
- Helped mentor and train Junior Engineers on best practices
- Led engineering team in creating Incyte's Node.js lightweight, easy-to-use SDK
- Designed and built Incyte's real-time, scalable, serverless streaming system, reducing developer manhours by 25%
- Designed and built Incyte's distributed DB using Druid Db and EC2, resulting in 7x faster queries
- Designed Incyte's ML infrastructure, including our Gemini Models
- · Helped lead marketing efforts and developer outreach, helping to win 10 beta-testing accounts
- Led integration with Stripe for payment processing
- Helped lead design decisions for Incyte's UI

CTO/Co-Founder

FoodEase Restaurant Analytics & Management - Boonton, NJ September 2020 to August 2021

- Designed FoodEase's infrastructure on AWS
- Helped to reduce operational costs by implementing a serverless architecture where applicable, reducing developer man-hours by almost 40%
- Designed FoodEase's analytics engine, a real time analytics engine capable of customer segmentation & item recommendation in order to extend customer's time in the restaurant, resulting in more 10% more per check for our beta customers
- Implemented Redis to facilitate real-time communication between servers and kitchen staff when taking orders, reducing wait times and improving efficiency by 35%
- Led automation efforts to create services to enable faster reordering of food for restaurants
- · Led efforts to integrate with custom hardware using Flutter & Android libraries for support

Business Intelligence Consultant

NPAW - Manhattan, NY February 2020 to July 2020

• Managed accounts for major telco & media companies across North America & APAC

- Various machine learning projects based around prediction & time series forecasting
- Developed a new methodology for calculating error thresholds in customer-facing alerts
- · Helped coordinate account strategies with CSMs and CES for several major corporate accounts
- Worked with customers' engineering and operations teams to create dashboards, deliver presentations on insights, and develop actionable reporting

Analyst

ZT Systems - Secaucus, NJ October 2018 to October 2019

- -Use data-driven analysis to determine ideal pricing strategies and markups to ensure company growth, while working with multiple teams to ensure ideal data collection.
- -Pull data from multiple sources using SQL as well as via Python and Scala in an effort to better-maintain cost prediction per unique SKU configuration.
- -Led project to create new data warehouse, as well as custom built business logic engine via Apache Spark, leading to more efficient cost predictions as well as better customer demand predictions.
- -Led efforts to automate day-to-day tactical operations including executive reports, customer-facing quotes, and analytics to support strategic decisions, leading to increased account efficiency.
- -Used Django to build a real-time dashboard to track cost refresh progress, EOL part IDs, and SKU configurations.

Data Analyst

Independent Contractor September 2016 to October 2018

- Used Scala, Apache Spark and Apache Kafka to create a stream-based analytics service to create near real time dashboards within the food service industry.
- Used Python to create and refine machine learning models to predict customer churn and supply-chain failures for e-commerce group.
- Used Leaflet.js, Google Analytics, Demographic data and Python to create a real-time map of web traffic for marketing research.
- Created interactive user dashboards using R and RShiny to replace excel reports in favor of an interactive sandbox for executives.
- Used Python to create tools designed to normalize and clean data for a team of junior financial analysts.
- Worked with the following data types: Marketing, Food Industry, Finance

Education

BA in Political Science

Drew University

Skills

- Python (6 years)
- Scala (2 years)
- SQL (3 years)
- Tableau (3 years)
- Apache Spark (3 years)
- Machine Learning (3 years)
- Data Analysis (8 years)
- ETL (3 years)
- Git (3 years)
- AWS (4 years)
- JavaScript (3 years)
- APIs (4 years)
- REST
- TypeScript (2 years)
- Node.js
- React
- GitHub
- Docker

Assessments

Spreadsheets with Microsoft Excel — Expert

May 2019

Excel knowledge including common tools, PivotTables, conditional & nested formulas, and custom visuals.

Full results: Expert

Data Scientist — Expert

October 2019

Interpreting and producing graphs, identifying trends, and drawing justifiable conclusions from data.

Full results: Expert

Logic & critical thinking — Highly Proficient

January 2020

Using logic to solve problems. Full results: <u>Highly Proficient</u>

Spreadsheets with Microsoft Excel — Expert

July 2020

Excel knowledge including common tools, PivotTables, conditional & nested formulas, and custom visuals.

Full results: Expert

Analyzing Data — **Highly Proficient**

July 2020

Interpreting and producing graphs, identifying trends, and drawing justifiable conclusions from data.

Full results: <u>Highly Proficient</u>

Indeed Assessments provides skills tests that are not indicative of a license or certification, or continued development in any professional field.